ascensus.com 2009-08-16

# Ascensus

| 

Home >> Privacy Policy

Click Here for AscensusSM Policy Concerning NonPublic Personal Consumer Information. 

Ascensus is committed to the privacy interests of users of this website. This privacy statement summarizes the privacy practices and procedures Ascensus has adopted. Ascensus is the sole owner of the information collected on this website. 

INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE

Ascensus collects information from its users at several different points on this website. The extent and type of information Ascensus receives from its users depends on the users' actions when visiting this website. 

Ascensus uses Internet Protocol ("IP") addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track users' movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

At some places in this Web-site cookies are used. For example, Ascensus' Shopping Cart and Online Ordering System use HTTP cookies to keep track of your order. A "cookie" is a method to pass information between the server and your web browser when you travel from web page to web page. This cookie information is stored on your hard drive in a special directory created when you installed your web browser. This information can only be passed to the website that created it. No other website can access this information. For example, if www.ascensus.com creates the cookie, only www.ascensus.com can access this cookie, and www.ascensus.com is not able to access cookies created by other sites. No personally identifiable information is stored by Ascensus in the cookies we create. 

In addition, cookies created by Ascensus are designed to be automatically deleted when the session terminates, except for a special cookie that may be set to tell us your browser is capable of using session HTTP cookies. The session will terminate when your web browser is closed or, if the browser is not closed, through the built in session expiration date. The built in expiration date will automatically delete the cookies a few hours after they have been created. 

Most web browsers can be configured to reject cookies, or to notify you if a cookie is sent to you. If you are not sure whether your web browser has these capabilities you should contact the software manufacturer or your Internet service provider. If a user rejects a cookie, certain areas of the website may not function properly. The affected areas may include but are not limited to the following: inability to access certain areas of the website, inconvenience of having to enter personal information more often, and navigation ability throughout the website. 

LINKS

This website may contain links to other websites. Ascensus does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy policies of such other websites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave this website and to read the privacy statements of each linked website. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this website. 

CHILDREN

Ascensus understands the importance of protecting children's privacy. This website is not intentionally designed for or directed at children 13 years of age or younger. It is our policy never to knowingly collect or maintain information about anyone under the age of 13. 

REVISION OF PRIVACY STATEMENT

Ascensus reserves the right to modify this privacy statement at any time. If Ascensus changes this privacy statement, Ascensus will post notification of the change on the Homepage of this Web-site. Users should review this privacy statement regularly. 

CONTACT INFORMATION

If you have any questions, concerns, or suggestions regarding this privacy statement contact us at:  
[commsoft@ascensus.com ](mailto:commsoft@ascensus.com) or  
Ascensus  
P.O. Box 979  
Brainerd, MN 56401  
Last modified: June 16, 2008 

AscensusSM and the AscensusSM logo are service marks and are used under license by Ascensus, Inc.
